William A Torres Amesty email: wtamesty@hotmail.com Phone: +1 (630) 605-9027

Bio: http://us.milliman.com/Consultants/?cid=84886

EDUCATION

La Universidad del Zulia (Maracaibo, Venezuela)

Roosevelt University (Chicago, IL USA)

Bachelor of Science: Physics

Graduation Date: April 2012

Roosevelt University (Chicago, IL USA)

Masters of Science: Actuarial Sciences

Graduation Date: May 10, 2016

SUMMARY

Actuarial Analyst with 3 years experience and 5 exams (CAS), and prior 3 years experience as a IT/Software developer. In my experience working in Consulting, I've been exposed to a variety of projects such as Reserving, Pricing and Predictive Analytics on the Actuarial side; and software development, system migrations, reporting on the IT side.

Currently I'm focused on Predictive Analytics and the development of Front-End solutions such as dashboards, Virtual Machines, Databases. A sample Data Visualization project showing interactive graphics using HTML and Javascript can be illustrated in this blog article: http://www.milliman.com/insight/2017/Making-predictive-analytics-work-for-you/.

ACTUARIAL EXAMS (CAS)

1, 2, 3F, MAS I, MAS II, VE, VF (awaiting results for Exam 5).

WORK EXPERIENCE



Milliman, Inc. (Chicago, IL USA)

May 2015 - Present

Actuarial Analyst

- Work on reserving projects for self-insured and large deductible clients for Workers' Compensation, Warranties, General Liability, Property Liability and Auto Liability coverages.
- Perform Rate Indication analysis and Build rating plans using GLMs for Financial an Specialty lines.
- Work on-site as an outsource contractor for a large P&C International Insurance Company (Allianz AGCS), assisting the
 Actuarial team to coordinate efforts with the IT department in a System migration.
- Developed a Cloud based Front-End solution for clients, which implements real time Predictive Models in their Claim Management operations through the use of Virtual Machines, Databases and Web Apps.
- Drafted client reports and presentations as well as other deliverables for clients, including proposals for potential projects.



FONAG (Quito, Ecuador)

March 2013 - August 2013

Assistant Consultant

- Implemented and updated Hydrologic Models (Water Stress) in the Quito basin, using ArcGIS model builder.
- Assessed Statistical Analysis and Data Homogenization for local Climate and Hydrology institutes.
- Drafted reports and presentations involving risk assessments and maps, aimed for decision makers.



VSOFT C.A. (Maracaibo, Venezuela)

November 2011 - August 2014

IT/Software Developer

- Developed and Maintain ad-hoc applications for different purposes: Administrative, Accounting, Inventory, etc.
- Build and Maintain Websites and WebApps.
- Built Reports and Queries suited for Client needs.
- Performed System and Database migrations.

SKILLS

Actuarial

- **Excel:** Used widely in my experience as an Actuarial Analyst to perform Reserving and Rate Indication Analysis.
- Word: Drafted reports and deliverables for clients.
- Powerpoint: Make presentations aimed to show results to Clients, and to illustrate proposals for potential projects.

Programming/Technical

- Web Programming: Built websites using HTML and Javascript for web interaction.
- **Data Visualization:** preference for web-based visualizations made in HTML/JavaScript using Highcharts.js, but also familiar with commercial BI vendors such as Tableau, PowerBI, Domo, etc.
- R Programming Language: Advanced level and used for a wide range of Actuarial analysis. Including projects involving Predictive modeling, pricing and ratemaking. Implement R scripts in Virtual Machines to automatize scoring process.
- Python: Intermediate level, used for data manipulation when dealing with large datasets.
- SQL Language: Built queries for Reports, Data Migration, Stored Procedures, Triggers.

Languages

• English (professional proficiency), Spanish (native) and French (Advanced).